Guide to the David Borden scores, 1952-2017.
Borden, David scores
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Borden scores, 1952-2017.
14-20-4107
Borden, David
2.8 cubic feet.
Score sheets, CD's, a DVD, posters.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Original manuscript scores, CD's, DVD's and other media.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Music. David Borden was educated at the Eastman School of Music and Harvard University and was a Fulbright scholar in Berlin, studying at the Hochschule fur Musik. His first composition teachers were jazz musicians Jimmy Giuffre and Jaki Byard. He is the retired founder and Director of the Digital Music Program at Cornell. In 1969 he founded Mother Mallard's Portable Masterpiece Co., the world's first synthesizer ensemble, with the support of Robert Moog. His Continuing Story of Counterpoint, a twelve-part cycle of pieces for synthesizers, acoustic instruments, and voice has been called the "Goldberg Variations of minimalism." He also composed part of the soundtrack for The Exorcist (1973) and other films. His music is available on the Cuneiform, New World Records, Lameduck, and Arbiter labels.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Original manuscript scores including "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" (9 parts), "Dialogues", "Counterpoint for Flute, Cello, and Harp", 1978, "Enfield in Winter", "C-A-G-E", "I Trill Tunes", "Le Tombeau de Josquin", "CAIRN for JFK", "Trudymusic", "The Force (That Through the Green Fuse Drives the Flower)", "Heaven - Kept Soul", "Double Portrait", "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass", "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio", "Twelve Preludes and Fugues".
CD's include "Earth Journeys", Vol. 1-12 and other works. Also, a poster depicting a performance of a composition written for a Moog synthesizer, and silk screens of 2 Mother Mallard Concerts and 1 self portrait.
Also, an unmixed master VTR cassette of David Borden and the Mother Mallard Band, September 16, 1988.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Borden, David, 1938-; Borden, David, 1938-
Subjects:
Synthesizer music.; Composers -- United States -- 20th century.; Composers; Synthesizer music
Places:
United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Scores
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Score Sheets
Box 1, 3, 4, 6
Series II. CD's, DVD's and other media
Box 2, 5
Series III. Other material
Box 3, Mapcase Folder 1
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Score Sheets
  - "Dialogues", 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Enfield in Winter", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Counterpoint For Flute, Cello and Harp", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part I, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part II, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part III, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part IV [unfinished], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part V, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part VI, orchestral version, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part VI, piano version, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part VII, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part VIII, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint" - Part IX, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "C-A-G-E" - Part I, II, III, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "I Trill Tunes" - for 1 or 2 keyboard instruments, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    3 copies
  - "Le Tombeau de Josquin", 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "CAIRN for JFK", 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Trudymusic", 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Force (That Through the Green Fuse Drives the Flower)" - bound score sheets, n.d. (Box 4)
  - "Heaven - Kept Soul" - Score, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Heaven - Kept Soul" - Piano, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Heaven - Kept Soul" - USB 88-Key, MIDI Controller, Keyboard 1, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Heaven - Kept Soul" - USB 88-Key, MIDI Controller, Keyboard 2, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Double Portrait" (for 2 piano) - Score, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Double Portrait" (for 2 pianos) - Piano 1, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Double Portrait" (for 2 pianos) - Piano 2, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass" - Score, 2011-2014 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass" - Keyboard 1, 2011-2014 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass" - Keyboard 2, 2011-2014 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass" - Keyboard 3, 2011-2014 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio", 2014 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio" - Oboe, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio" - Violin, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio" - Viola, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Quartet in Four Movements for Oboe and String Trio" - Violoncello, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Heaven-kept Soul - Piano solo and 2 88-key MIDI controller keyboards attached via USB to laptops running Reason 7 or higher, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Twelve Preludes and Fugues - for two pianos, piano 1, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Twelve Preludes and Fugues - for two pianos, piano 2, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 12 Preludes and Fugues - for two pianos, volume one, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 12 Preludes and Fugues - for two pianos, volume two, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Series II. CD's, DVD's and other media
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 1, n.d.; CD-2370 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 2, n.d.; CD-2371 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 3, n.d.; CD-2372 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 4, n.d.; CD-2373 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 5, n.d.; CD-2374 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 6, n.d.; CD-2375 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 7, n.d.; CD-2376 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 8, n.d.; CD-2377 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 9, n.d.; CD-2378 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 10, n.d.; CD-2379 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 11, n.d.; CD-2380 (Box 2)
  - "Earth Journeys, variations on Happy Birthday", Volume 12, n.d.; CD-2846 (Box 2)
  - "Heaven-Kept Soul", n.d.; CD-2381 (Box 2)
  - Flash drive, "Heaven-Kept Soul", n.d.; HD-3 (Box 2)
  - Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass, 2011-2014; DVD-1692 (Box 5)
  - "David Borden and Edward Murry play Gershwin", n.d.; CD-2801 (Box 5)
  - "A Tribute to Duke Ellington", 1999; CD-2802 (Box 5)
  - "Night and Day", n.d.; CD-2803 (Box 5)
  - "As Time Goes By", 1997; CD-2804 (Box 5)
  - "The Continuing Story of Counterpoint", parts 1-4, 8, n.d.; CD-2805 (Box 5)
  - "Mother Mallard's Portable Masterpiece, co. 1970-1973", 1999; CD-2806 (Box 5)
  - "Mother Mallard, Like a Duck to Water", 2001; CD-2807 (Box 5)
  - "Variations on a Theme of Philip Glass", 2011-2014; CD-2808 (Box 5)
  - "Music for Amplified Keyboard Instruments", 2014; CD-2809 (Box 5)
  - "Cayuga Night Music", 1993, 2002; CD-2810 (Box 5)
  - "Borden on Borden", n.d.; CD-2811 (Box 5)
  - David Borden and the Mother Mallard Band, unmixed master, 1988-09-16; V-10949; VTR cassette
- Series III. Other material
  - Silk screens of a self portrait and 2 Mother Mallard concert posters, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poster depicting a performance of a composition written for a Moog synthesizer, 1975 (Map-case Folder 1)